<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pragun Bhutani's Blog</title>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.pragunbhutani.in/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://blog.pragunbhutani.in</link>
    <description>Here, occasionally, stuff will be written.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 05:30:00 +0630</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Google Summer of Code 2013 - Let's Mobilize Wikidata! - A Summary</title>
      <link>http://blog.pragunbhutani.in/articles/google-summer-of-code-2013-wrap-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 05:30:00 +0630</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pragunbhutani.in/articles/google-summer-of-code-2013-wrap-up/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About 6 months ago, while I was recovering from a motorbike accident, a friend of mine encouraged me to try out for Google Summer of Code.
Now, I&amp;#39;d known about the program for a couple of years but had never actually considered applying. All the people that I had ever known
to get into this program (5 peers from my University) were such better developers than me in every conceivable way and I never really imagined
that I had any chance of actually getting accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I took the plunge and what followed after has been one of the most interesting summers of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wikidata and I&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;![Wikidata Logo](Wikidata Logo.png)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stumbled accross Wikidata completely by chance while browsing through project ideas. To be frank, I had no idea about Wikidata before this
summer. But as the universe would have it, I had begun taking an interest in Ontologies and Knowledge Graphs not too long ago and here I was
looking at something that was just that! I browsed through Wikidata and I think that was it. I knew that that was what I wanted to work on
for GSoC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mobilize Wikidata - The Project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My project was aimed at bringing Wikidata to mobiles. Wikidata is a relatively new project and there&amp;#39;s a lot that needs to be done in terms of
improving the accessiblity and the user experience. Making Wikidata accessible on mobile phones is one of the things targeted at making it
easier to access (and hopefully in the near future, add all forms of rich and diverse data).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried installing Mobile Frontend on top of Wikibase to see what kind of a result that would give us and we landed up with a basketful of horrors.
Some of those were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The view of labels and description was broken. The entity ID was visible before every label and while this was hidden by JS in desktop view,
it was sitting right there in Mobile View.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statement view was completely broken. Statements and their values weren&amp;#39;t formatted at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statements couldn&amp;#39;t be edited or added.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users couldn&amp;#39;t change languages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The layout was broken because MobileFrontend wasn&amp;#39;t equipped to handle data from Wikibase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/User:Pragunbhutani/GSoC_2013_Proposal&quot;&gt;Project proposal on Mediawiki.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Proposed deliverables and solution approach&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, I had proposed to create a no-JS version of entity view because I had believed that JS not rendering UIs properly on mobile devices was
the cause of all the damage.
Over the course of the project, it was decided that a better solution approach would be from me to develop a new mobile skin for Wikibase.
The skin in question could extend SkinMobile from MobileFrontend and have whatever extra was necessary to properly render the content from Wikibase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gives us an additional advantage as the Wikibase Mobile skin would automatically benefit from changes made to MobileFrontend and they would
automatically be mirrored downstream. Further, not having to tinker about with EntityView code meant that there would be a smaller chance of me breaking
something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, I think that was a very good decision because a separate skin is so much more maintainable and if someone else feels like coming in to
contribute, they‘ll have a much easier time understanding everything that’s happening there so they may go about their hacking without wasting the
hours they would&amp;#39;ve spent had they been looking for the changes I made to EntityView code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Progress made thus far&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I‘m pleased to report that I’ve made some good progress on the skin. While it&amp;#39;s not completely ready to be deployed, I think that the first iteration
of the skin is about 95% there and I plan on getting the remaining work done ASAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve set up &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikidata-mobile-tester.instance-proxy.wmflabs.org/w/index.php?title=Main_Page&amp;amp;mobileaction=toggle_view_mobile&quot;&gt;a demo&lt;/a&gt; on a labs instance for those who&amp;#39;d like to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The skin is currently based on the following UI mockup:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.pragunbhutani.in/articles/google-summer-of-code-2013-wrap-up/UI-Mockup-v2.png&quot; alt=&quot;UI-Mockup-v2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A copy of the skin may be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pragunbhutani/WikibaseMobile&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://git.wikimedia.org/summary/mediawiki%2Fextensions%2FWikibaseMobile&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Installation instructions can be found on the github repo page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;d like to read more about the discussed solution approaches or project status updates, you can find more information on the following links:
&lt;em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/User:Pragunbhutani/GSoC_2013_Updates&quot;&gt;Project status updates&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/User:Pragunbhutani/GSoC_2013_Implementation_Approaches&quot;&gt;Discussions and solution approaches&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Future Development Ideas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s so much more that can be done to improve the usability and experience of Wikibase mobile! Here are a few ideas that I could think of
while working on the project and I plan to implement as many of these as I can over the coming months:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improving the UI of the mobile skin to be more consistent with Mobile Frontend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce a two column layout for tablets/bigger devices. Here&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/User:Pragunbhutani/GSoC_2013_Implementation_Approaches#UI_Mockup_v3&quot;&gt;an example&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have CSS3 handle animations instead of jQuery. jQuery on mobiles is troublesome!! In case an older device is trying to access the website,
one which can‘t handle CSS3 animations, we’ll not have any animations. Mobile Frontend works without animations by default, so that&amp;#39;s okay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check if I can use LESS and if I can, do so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure ‘Special’ pages work properly on mobiles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve the workflow of adding/editing content on mobiles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement a method for users to switch languages. Fortunately, because of the solution approach I‘ve taken, this shouldn’t be hard to do!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then there‘s a whole lot there could be done to ensure that EntityView and WikibaseMobile share more code than they do now, so there’s no doubling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve already been sharing my experience with a few juniors and my university and hopefully, some of them will get interested in contributing to it!
Who knows, maybe they could propose another GSoC project to improve upon my work in the coming years (I&amp;#39;d so love to mentor that)! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thank-Yous and Appreciation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would‘ve gotten absolutely no-where had I not had the support of the wonderful Wikimedia community. There are just so many people
who’ve helped me out in a hundred ways and more and I&amp;#39;d like to take a minute to say thank you!
This list isn‘t exhaustive by a long shot. I’ve had hours of help from people in the IRC channels, but here are just a few lines to some of the
people who helped me make this summer what it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My mentors - Karie Filbert and Jon Robson for being the incredibly patient and helpful people they are. I can&amp;#39;t imagine how Katie managed to keep a
patient head and answer the endless stream of questions I would direct at her. Not all the questions were very smart ones either! I bet Jon will agree,
given how much trouble I had trying to get the resourceLoader to include my CSS file. No matter how clichéed this sounds,
I would honestly have not been able to achieve even 1% of what I did had it not been for these guys and I&amp;#39;m truly thankful to them.
Thanks for being there guys, for being constantly accessible and for helping me navigate through the immense and complex code base, which I would have
definitely lost myself in otherwise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Wikidata team was incredibly fun to work with. Thanks for letting me attend those hangouts during the first few weeks of my project. They really
made me feel involved with the rest of the team and I was able to take ownership for this skin that I&amp;#39;ve been working on. Thank you Denny, Lydia, Hoo,
Daniel, Addshore for all the times you guys helped me on the IRC or gave me your feedback. I loved every bit of working with this team and you guys are
a huge part of the reason I want to stay on and contribute!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pau Giner, thanks for creating and sharing that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/User:Pragunbhutani/GSoC_2013_Implementation_Approaches#UI_Mockup_v3&quot;&gt;UI mockup&lt;/a&gt; with me. I absolutely loved it and it really helped me develop a vision for how I think Wikidata Mobile should work and look in the future. I even tried to
implement it at first, but had to stash it for the time being because I wasn‘t able to handle the two column layout properly. I think that the design would
work really work on tablets and implementing it is one of the things I’ve planned for the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sumana and Quim, thanks for all the times you helped and gave me your feedback back when I was first trying to understand how to contribute and
apply to GSoC. You guys make it so easy for a newbie to jump in and participate!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile team, for all the guidance and for that patch that allowed me to create a new skin by extending the classes of MobileFrontend. This project
could happen only because of that. Cheers!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brion, Nizil Shah, John Lewis, Hobofan, Tobias for the feedback you gave everytime I shared a possible implementation approach for disucussion.
Your inputs have had a really improtant role in shaping this project into what it turned out to be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A huge shout out to Ankur Saxena (@flyankur), &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/drecodeam&quot;&gt;Ankur Anand&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://vaidikkapoor.info/&quot;&gt;Vaidik&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://praveensingh.in/&quot;&gt;Praveen Singh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dash1291&quot;&gt;Ashish Dubey&lt;/a&gt; and the Open Source Developers Club at my university (JIIT OSDC) for teaching me about Open Source, for helping me with my application, for sharing so much knowledge and for being pretty cool people in general. :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mom and dad for the delicious meals and a million other things. Ridhi for having mom and dad take us out for so many of those meals! :D&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;…and everyone else who I interacted with during these past few months over the IRC or the mailing lists or the hangouts. You&amp;#39;re awesome!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Summer of Code 2013 - Mobilize Wikidata</title>
      <link>http://blog.pragunbhutani.in/articles/google-summer-of-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 05:30:00 +0630</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pragunbhutani.in/articles/google-summer-of-code/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It‘s with great excitement that I announce that I’ve been accepted into Google Summer of Code 2013.
I&amp;#39;m going to be working with the Wikimedia foundation on a project entitled “Mobilize Wikidata”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My project is aimed at extending Wikidata&amp;#39;s functionality to make it accessible on mobile devices.
Setting up Wikibase with MobileFrontend shows that while MobileFrontend can be used to achieve a mobile-friendly version of Wikidata,
some problems arise due to JS based UIs not rendering properly through MobileFrontend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan is to implement Wikibase without Javascript to make it compatible with MobileFrontend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details about the project can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/User:Pragunbhutani/GSoC_2013_Proposal&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I‘m really excited about the summer and all that it has to bring.
This is my first time working with an organization and code base of this scale and I’m sure it&amp;#39;s going to be a great experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be a good opportunity for me to learn how to enhance and improve upon existing code at such a huge scale.
Mediawiki follows a lot of good coding conventions so I‘m hoping it’ll improve my coding style as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, stay tuned to this category and I&amp;#39;ll keep reporting the progress of my project as it moves along.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suck, Squeeze, Bang, Blow.</title>
      <link>http://blog.pragunbhutani.in/articles/suck-squeeze-bang-blow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 05:30:00 +0630</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pragunbhutani.in/articles/suck-squeeze-bang-blow/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout my years of engineering, I&amp;#39;ve thought about this question a countless number of times. “Why did I decide to study engineering?” In part, it could have been because of all the promises of riches and glory that the life of an engineer brings, that we were told as kids in this country. How ironic it is to have such a multitude of engineers in a place so annoyingly under-engineered! I digress, sorry. That topic in itself deserves to be expounded upon in a series of articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, was it for the riches? I don‘t know. I don’t think so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I try to think back to the times when I was a kid and my mind wasn&amp;#39;t encumbered with illusions of reality, I realize that maybe this was the person I was meant to be from the get go. Right from the very beginning, I was interested in understanding how things (anything and everything) worked!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It began with my fascination with car engines, my first ‘Mechanix’ toy kit and the rabbit hole just kept on going deeper and deeper…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did a switch make the fan go round? Why does turning the knob make it go faster? How did the hairdresser‘s spray turn water into that fine, cool mist? What made aeroplanes fly? What exactly is ’fire&amp;#39; and why is it the way it is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can‘t remember a time in my life when I wasn’t pursuing one such curiosity or another. Like I said, I guess I was plonked into this world as a tinker destined to become an engineer some day. That unending desire to figure out the nuts and bolts of everything. When computers came along, I was naturally taken in by the wonders of this magical device that could make a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logo_(programming_language&quot;&gt;turtle&lt;/a&gt;#Turtle_and_graphics) draw all forms of shapes and figures by the command of a few words! That fascination sowed the seeds of what was to become my decision to study Computer Science at college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere during my first year though, I forgot about all of this. I think it was a fear of commitment that gripped me. Or maybe a nagging voice inside that kept telling me that I hadn‘t even been exposed to all that was ’out there‘ and all I could be. Four years of stumbling and wandering have brought me to this point where I’m once again aware of who I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I am not afraid.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skadool - Flexible scheduling powered by Plivo</title>
      <link>http://blog.pragunbhutani.in/articles/skadool-plivo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 05:30:00 +0630</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pragunbhutani.in/articles/skadool-plivo/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://plivo.com/&quot;&gt;Plivo&lt;/a&gt; is a great cloud platform that allows you to build powerful telephony apps in a breeze. Now I&amp;#39;m not much of a developer, but when I was asked to use it and build an app, I decided to give it a spin!
It was a little intimidating at first, but fortunately Plivo has very well documented code and a fantastic set of helper functions that made my job so much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea for my app came from the need to make sure that people don‘t miss courier deliveries. I, for one, hate it when I’ve purchased something online and miss the shipment when there&amp;#39;s noone there to receive it. Courier companies must not be very fond of it either, seeing as they have to then ship it all over again. Such a terrible waste of manpower hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How cool would it be if on the morning of your delivery, the courier-system could place an auto-generated IVR call or send a text to the delivery recipients asking them if they&amp;#39;d be available to receive their deliveries that day?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skadool is my attempt to create such an app. I‘ve used Plivo’s framework to power it. I added a small API(my first, in fact!) to it to allow potential courier companies to handle the CRUD of this list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code and documentation can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blotmandroid/skadool&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blotmandroid/skadool&quot;&gt;https://github.com/blotmandroid/skadool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I welcome any and all feedback! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming Hobbit</title>
      <link>http://blog.pragunbhutani.in/articles/becoming-hobbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 05:30:00 +0630</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pragunbhutani.in/articles/becoming-hobbit/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From this point on, I am going to proudly, ideologically and irrevocably become a hobbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn‘t one good reason that tells me that I shouldn’t do this. One the other hand, there are so many that compel me to! There‘re second breakfasts and mushrooms, there’s beer, more food in general and enough happiness to go around. Making the decision was the easy bit though. The hard part is actually doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, how does a person even go about doing something like this? Do I wait till things in life settle down so I can be happy and chilled out? But you can never be sure of that. There&amp;#39;s always something or the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, this is the first time I‘ve had to start thinking about taking responsibility for myself. I don’t know how things are going to pan out in the future. What if life never does really ‘settle down’? Even if it did, would I like it that way? It‘s like this journey that you have to begin and I think the only way I’m going to make it somewhere if I learn to take some joy in the road. Beer and second breakfasts can certainly help. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I think I‘m just going to wing it. Try to be happy about stuff, go about my jolly little trade and enjoy the small things as they pass by. Us Hobbits don’t have to ‘grow up’ till we‘re 30, so I think I can take things slow for now and enjoy the journey. I don’t know if it&amp;#39;ll work, but it seems good enough to warrant a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In line with that spirit, I&amp;#39;m sitting here with a hot cup of coffee on a deliciously cold evening, listening to nice music and writing down this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the hobbit&amp;#39;s life already.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sky Moves Sideways</title>
      <link>http://blog.pragunbhutani.in/articles/sky-moves-sideways/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 05:30:00 +0630</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pragunbhutani.in/articles/sky-moves-sideways/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like to look up at the sky sometimes. Not very often, but every now and then and especially at night. There are very few things that can blow your mind in the same way that a night sky can. It‘s not really the vastness or the blackness or the number of things out there that gets you. It’s this feeling of being disconnected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world that we interact with in our daily lives, the people that we meet and the things we do all seem so very strangely real in the face of the feeling that you get when you‘re looking up. Out there is a realm so unimaginably vast and complex and beautiful that I cannot even begin to comprehend. Yet, ours is a part of that larger world that goes on in ways that we understand so little of. I’ve never been able to put these two together and see them as one. Every time I‘ve tried to think and reason into this, I’ve always ended up with more questions than I began with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I‘ve imagined myself flying out at times, accelerating away from the Earth and Sun and the solar system as if gravity wasn’t even a thing. Those trips are always fun. You can go on for quite a while, marveling at the scale of things till you hit the “Roof problem” as I like to call it. The way I understand things, everything has to be inside something right? Like, if I was flying away from the Earth, I‘d be in the Solar System. Moving on, I’d pass Neptune and Pluto and then the Oort cloud. Further still, I‘d cross Proxima Centaury and eventually escape the Milky Way. Where to then? To the boundaries of our universe? What does that even mean? How can we be so sure that the universe isn’t inside something else? And what about the container of the universe… what is that thing inside of? The problem iterates upon itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I‘m not really sure where I was going with all this. If I had an idea at the beginning, I know it’s ‘out there’ somewhere but I‘m pretty sure I’ve lost it completely. The one thing that I&amp;#39;m really sure of though is that,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an infinite universe, the one thing sentient life cannot afford to have is a sense of proportion.
- Douglas Adams&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damn right it can&amp;#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slow, Steady, Persistent.</title>
      <link>http://blog.pragunbhutani.in/articles/slow-steady-persistent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 05:30:00 +0630</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pragunbhutani.in/articles/slow-steady-persistent/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I completed my first week of P90X today. It‘s this new workout plan that I’ve started following. I‘ve been in and out of things like this before but I don’t think that I‘ve ever stayed strong through an entire week. I’ve just got 84 more days to go now. Easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slow. Steady. Persistent. Those three words have been running through my head for the last couple of days. You see, there‘s always this huge gap between the person that you want to be and the person that you are. Same’s the case with me. A little over a month ago, I made the decision to start bridging that gap and the only way I think I&amp;#39;ll be able to do that is by being slow, steady and persistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I owe this realization to P90X perhaps. I‘ve really started enjoying the daily workouts and the fact that I don’t have to think about anything else while I‘m doing them. I’m not worried about how far I‘ve come along the program. I’m not worried about how I‘m going to go about finishing the entire program. I’m not trying to keep myself motivated to stick with the plan for the next 12 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to motivate myself to stick with it everyday. Every single day, and only one day at a time. Worrying can be such a handicap! What with our tendency to start looking at a task in its entirety and start worrying about how we&amp;#39;re going to go through with it. I now understand that breaking things into small portions makes them so much easier to manage. I sure hope this applies to things other than exercise programs as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s time for me to find out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>